[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0be", "question": "What US state includes the telephone area code 602?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d1d", "question": "What popular musician's last name is Douglas?", "answer": "Ashanti", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb1beeff497e33de8057919", "question": "How many points did LeBron James score in his very first NBA game?", "answer": "25", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008c0acf842fa4c4ba969c", "question": "Mysophobia is the irrational fear of what?", "answer": "Contamination", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac71", "question": "Where were scissors believed to be first invented?", "answer": "Ancient Egypt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c75b", "question": "Dermatology studies which part of the human body?", "answer": "The skin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe93b8e6bd93ce3a4e5f6a4", "question": "What did Theodoric of Freiberg correctly explain?", "answer": "Rainbow phenomenon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ca3e1e44f0f6af5b066645", "question": "In mathematics which prefix refers to 10 to the power of minus 15?", "answer": "Femto", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133915d", "question": "Who directed the movie \"Apocalypse Now\"?", "answer": "Francis Ford Coppola", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bb3", "question": "How many symphonies did Beethoven compose?", "answer": "9", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60078b410eee65b76b9f2665", "question": "Which world leader, who came to power in 1949, is famous for his \"Little Red Book\"?", "answer": "Mao Zedong, or Mao Tse-tung.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b3234babf195a31e15d73a8", "question": "Which chemical element gets its name from the Greek for \"Violet-colored\"?", "answer": "Iodine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338da9", "question": "Plato's \"Apology\" consists of what man's defence against a capital charge?", "answer": "Socrates'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8f5", "question": "What US state's civil law is most closely based on the Napoleonic Code?", "answer": "Louisiana's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe733fdeec85e375820b22a", "question": "In which battle did Chinese general Zhang Hongfan destroy the last fleet of the Southern Song Dynasty?", "answer": "Battle of Yamen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe93ccf6bd93ce3a4e5f6ac", "question": "What is the smallest biological unit of a living organism?", "answer": "Cell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b299e662d71a53650fda", "question": "What is James Bond's preferred type of martini?", "answer": "Vesper", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c870", "question": "What is a Chinese gooseberry?", "answer": "A kiwifruit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf1", "question": "What year was actor Heath Ledger born in?", "answer": "1979", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e96917ccba3ffe45786ef", "question": "Galt MacDermot wrote the music for what 1967 musical?", "answer": "Hair", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6da", "question": "What\u2019s the term for mass per unit volume?", "answer": "Density", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339798", "question": "Who did Michael Jackson marry in May 1994?", "answer": "Lisa Marie Pressley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133951d", "question": "Who voiced Esmeralda in the 1996 Disney movie \"The Hunchback of Notre Dame\"?", "answer": "Demi Moore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133932f", "question": "Who shot JR?", "answer": "Kristin Shepard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bba", "question": "Who went down to Hades to rescue his wife Eurydice?", "answer": "Orpheus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fde", "question": "What 1959 Dave Brubeck Quartet piece borrows its name from its unusual time signature?", "answer": "Take Five", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe522ce1bf59ab7d2e380eb", "question": "What is mistletoe for according to Polish folklore?", "answer": "Ward off evil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac29", "question": "Which European city is served by Galileo Galilei Airport?", "answer": "Pisa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339365", "question": "30 Rock refers to what in the TV series \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "30 Rockefeller Plaza", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65723ae7e414034b5aed7", "question": "Where were the Declaration of Independence, the Constitution, and the Bill of Rights stored during World War II?", "answer": "Fort Knox", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e9", "question": "What was writer and war hero T.E. Lawrence popularly known as?", "answer": "Lawrence of Arabia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a096", "question": "Which film features the line, \"I could have been a contender\"?", "answer": "On the Waterfront", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fda", "question": "What TV show did \"The Law and Harry McGraw\" spin off from?", "answer": "Murder, She Wrote", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4bd", "question": "What part of the eye changes shape in LASIK surgery?", "answer": "The cornea", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a63", "question": "Who played Rocky's wife, Adrian, in the \"Rocky\" films?", "answer": "Talia Shire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c23f", "question": "What do peacocks mate with?", "answer": "Peahens", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fde52b6c6c6b019850c9a98", "question": "In Proverbs, when Solomon refers to the lazy, he tells the sluggard to look to what insect for an example?", "answer": "Ant", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ce", "question": "What is the lowest point in the United States?", "answer": "Death Valley, California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff14259b0ee8c595b6d39ac", "question": "In the \"Jack and the Beanstalk\" fairy tale, what did Jack trade for five magic beans?", "answer": "A cow", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ded251ea2747c8aff16d3c", "question": "What structure in the back of the brain governs motor control?", "answer": "Cerebellum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b218", "question": "Who was assassinated by Giuseppe Zangara?", "answer": "Anton Cermak", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59523f68736d4be723796b58", "question": "What year were the Canada's Juno Awards first awarded?", "answer": "1970", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab99c1f21a8909e5c332d33", "question": "Who is novelist Helen Fielding's most famous character?", "answer": "Bridget Jones", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b637", "question": "What was the first name of the real Chef Boyardee?", "answer": "Hector", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc0cb7469bb8041d07a055", "question": "What gives the drink known as a \"Black Cow\" its color?", "answer": "Coffee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b9", "question": "In 1901, William McKinley was assassinated in which US state?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea3572ff048f679a45ab02", "question": "What color is Mars\u2019 sunset?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015f287fe83fe1f2a824c1a", "question": "Saint Valentine is the patron saint of which specific disease?", "answer": "Epilepsy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133920c", "question": "In which TV show is the local fast-food restaurant called \"The Chum Bucket\"?", "answer": "SpongeBob SquarePants", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3af", "question": "Which British designer invented the Dual Cyclone bagless vacuum cleaner?", "answer": "James Dyson", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6b4", "question": "What type of bird is the Brown Thrasher?", "answer": "Songbird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1f2", "question": "What is the name of the rabbit in the 1942 film, \"Bambi\"?", "answer": "Thumper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d73", "question": "What ship was commanded by Jack Sparrow?", "answer": "Black Pearl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3e6", "question": "What was the name of the B-29 bomber that dropped an atomic bomb on the city of Nagasaki during WWII?", "answer": "Bockscar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339597", "question": "Musical duo Kaoma introduced the world to which dance in 1989?", "answer": "Lambada", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a67e", "question": "Which US state is home to Wind Cave?", "answer": "South Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59220369a4edfd43a087ade2", "question": "Marzipan is made of which ground nut?", "answer": "Almond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febae847e83c707845b20f6", "question": "Which insect uses the Milky Way to navigate?", "answer": "African dung beetle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58c9f76cb4e2c7fbd3896749", "question": "What company\u2019s tea shipment was destroyed during the Boston Tea Party in 1773?", "answer": "East India Company", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe530031bf59ab7d2e38118", "question": "How many states does the Hoover Dam power?", "answer": "3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ab", "question": "Who does Emma Watson play in the Harry Potter films?", "answer": "Hermione", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec86bcec223966ae8f8811", "question": "Who was the first female artist in history to have 4 consecutive singles from one album reach the Top 5 in the Billboard Hot 100?", "answer": "Cyndi Lauper's 1983 classic \"She's So Unusual\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b6", "question": "What movie starring Tobey Maguire and Michael Caine won a Best Adapted Screenplay Oscar for John Irving?", "answer": "The Cider House Rules", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c11c", "question": "What year did the US first host the Summer Olympic Games?", "answer": "1904", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea788fff048f679a45abdb", "question": "What is a \"Haricot Vert\"?", "answer": "A tender string bean", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393bb", "question": "What was Robert De Niro's nickname in the movie \"Casino\"?", "answer": "Ace", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5e726ce05a3942286e33", "question": "Beyonce's 2011 hit \"Party\" features which founding member of OutKast?", "answer": "Andre 3000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601370631381754895396381", "question": "In the 1990 film \"Home Alone\", Joe Pesci's character, Harry Lime, was named after\u00a0a character from\u00a0which Orson Welles' film?", "answer": "The Third Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc30dec223966ae8f887a", "question": "Cricket stars Clyde Walcott, Everton Weekes and Frank Worrell were all born in which city within 18 months of each other?", "answer": "Bridgetown, Barbados", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6017382d44491cbd7c5a1795", "question": "What was the first U.S. state to ban billboards?", "answer": "Hawaii -- Billboards were banned in Hawaii in 1927.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339afb", "question": "What rock musician got his stage name from the yellow and black jerseys he used to wear?", "answer": "Sting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa38", "question": "What is the capital of the Democratic Republic of Congo?", "answer": "Kinshasa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339965", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Comic Book Guy's real full name?", "answer": "Jeffrey Albertson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c9", "question": "Emanuel Rosenfeld , Maurice Strauss, and Graham Jackson are better known as whom?", "answer": "The Pep Boys", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef93fe6ce05a3942286e93", "question": "What show did \"TV Guide\" name the \"best TV show of all time\" in 2002?", "answer": "\"Seinfeld\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a6b", "question": "On \"Saturday Night Live\", from what country did the Coneheads claim to be from?", "answer": "France", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c0", "question": "What material is produced from the gossypium shrub?", "answer": "Cotton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5971debf89261e916c8e09a3", "question": "The beaver is the national emblem of which country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b5f5e662d71a53651000", "question": "What was the most popular type of paint during the Renaissance?", "answer": "Oil", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acf0", "question": "Which president signed the legislation to create the Secret Service?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec26578dc25ca9e12ef64a", "question": "How many millimeters are in an inch?", "answer": "25.4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bbc", "question": "Who was the twin brother of Artemis?", "answer": "Apollo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f10", "question": "Baroness, Duke, Storm Shadow, and Snake Eyes were characters from which 1980's cartoon?", "answer": "G.I. Joe: A Real American Hero", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b61c", "question": "The fez originated from what country?", "answer": "Morocco", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b29b", "question": "What bird did Ben Franklin suggest replace the bald eagle as a national emblem?", "answer": "The wild turkey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a28", "question": "What car model gave its name to an alien in \"The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy\"?", "answer": "Ford Prefect", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e07", "question": "What 1993 movie's title character is actually out-of-work voice actor Daniel Hillard?", "answer": "Mrs. Doubtfire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8ad3101dd7bf43be5e777", "question": "Who invented the color wheel?", "answer": "Sir Isaac Newton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd668d1a5bfecdd737e0873", "question": "What was the name of the Beatles' first studio album?", "answer": "Cargo House", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b372dc1c3f17ccc40c8e28", "question": "Rodney Dangerfield, Phil LaMarr and Randy Quaid starred in which 2005 film?", "answer": "Back by Midnight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b5", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is the three-eyed fish named?", "answer": "Blinky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a883", "question": "What Blue Ridge peak in North Carolina is the highest point east of the Mississippi?", "answer": "Mount Mitchell", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff20f3c31a458464a93c42f", "question": "What novella was the inspiration for the film \"Apocalypse Now\"?", "answer": "\"Heart of Darkness\" by Joseph Conrad", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d116fb4fea7fe947a22275", "question": "Mickey Mouse is known as what in Italy?", "answer": "Topolino", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339943", "question": "What is the first rule in the movie \"Fight Club\"?", "answer": "You don't talk about Fight Club", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ab1", "question": "What type of family pet gets boiled in a pot of water in the movie \"Fatal Attraction\"?", "answer": "A rabbit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b83a", "question": "What food got its name by the way it hung in bunches like grapes?", "answer": "Grapefruit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909cfedbb53d1af658864f7", "question": "What was the name of the toy store in the film \"Home Alone 2\"?", "answer": "Duncan\u2019s Toy Chest", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab26", "question": "What separates Madagascar from Mozambique?", "answer": "Mozambique Channel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b51c", "question": "What is Whisky distilled from?", "answer": "Fermented grain mash", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea8", "question": "What's the Japanese name for a potentially poisonous delicacy made from puffer fish meat?", "answer": "Fugu", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65d191f3c0ead6880d618", "question": "The Australian federation was formed on what date?", "answer": "January 1, 1901", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a23d", "question": "What was Elton John's fourth studio album?", "answer": "Madman Across the Water", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339867", "question": "In Disney's \"Dumbo\", what is it that Dumbo is made fun of for?", "answer": "His large ears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b27", "question": "What 1991 River Phoenix/Keanu Reeves film took its title from lyrics in a B-52's song?", "answer": "My Own Private Idaho", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a063", "question": "Before becoming a singer, what was Perry Como's profession?", "answer": "Barber", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008da2df4f3bc4a292f8613", "question": "Why did the British royals change their family name to the House of Windsor in 1917?", "answer": "The original name, Saxe-Coburgs, was derived from Queen Victoria's German husband, Albert. That did not sit well during World War I.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a3", "question": "The annual Miss America Pageant is held in what city?", "answer": "Atlantic City", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f90", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"The Heart is a Lonely Hunter\"?", "answer": "Sandra Locke", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa06", "question": "What lies between Stockholm and Riga?", "answer": "The Baltic Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8b5", "question": "Proteus orbits what planet of the solar system?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa5563c73aa70ea0b70b23", "question": "Which English city was once known as Duroliponte?", "answer": "Cambridge", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133958e", "question": "What is Ben Stiller's character's last name in the movie \"Meet the Parents\"?", "answer": "Focker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca38", "question": "Which element is fourth on the periodic table?", "answer": "Beryllium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d13", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"The Adventure Home\"?", "answer": "Free Willy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac82", "question": "Who founded the city of Philadelphia?", "answer": "William Penn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7e87cb24f84e0b9f9ffc4", "question": "What process involves the heating of milk to a temperature of about 70 degrees Celsius?", "answer": "Pasteurisation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be2c", "question": "The Chicago Bulls take the court to \"Sirius\", an instrumental track by what prog-rock band?", "answer": "The Alan Parsons Project", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339803", "question": "What movie did rappers Ice Cube & Ice T star in?", "answer": "Tresspass", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c540", "question": "Alfred Nobel is credited with the invention of what?", "answer": "Dynamite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e0d2fe83fe1f2a824b92", "question": "Against which country did the Soviet Union instigate an armed conflict in late 1939?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f10401dd7bf43be5e802", "question": "What common household item inspired the soles of Nike's first running shoes?", "answer": "Waffle iron", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce7", "question": "What is Mr. Snuffleupagus's given name?", "answer": "Aloysius", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76861eec85e375820b2a0", "question": "What is the tallest peak in Colorado?", "answer": "Mt. Elbert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd66377a5bfecdd737e0850", "question": "How long have dogs been domesticated?", "answer": "15,000 years", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5cb70cb0f96e155acab35d2e", "question": "What are the only two states where MLB teams play during spring training?", "answer": "Arizona and Florida", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea6", "question": "Who became the earl of Stockton on his 90th birthday?", "answer": "Harold Macmillan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a218", "question": "Who won the first UK version of \"Big Brother\"?", "answer": "Craig Phillips", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133931a", "question": "In the 1967 movie \"Cool Hand Luke\", how many hard-boiled eggs does Lucas eat in one hour?", "answer": "50", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb82", "question": "Canfield, Klondike, and Pyramid are variations of what card game?", "answer": "Solitaire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa38c9c73aa70ea0b70ad5", "question": "Basundi is a dairy product that is popular in which part of the world?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391af", "question": "Who dramatically kissed Halle Berry on stage when he won Best Actor?", "answer": "Adrien Brody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008fa6cf842fa4c4ba96bf", "question": "In what Australian state would you find the city of Launceston?", "answer": "Tasmania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ecaea45790ded87bb38fd8e", "question": "When measured from its underwater base, what is the tallest mountain?", "answer": "Mauna Kea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c77ce4f24f0f7a362efd546", "question": "A-ha and Edward Grieg hail from what country ", "answer": "Norway", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa3d9fc73aa70ea0b70af5", "question": "Where did the name \"California\" likely originate?", "answer": "In a romance novel. Spanish author Garci Ord\u00f3\u00f1ez de Montalvo named a fictional island oasis California; its queen was Califia.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8df", "question": "The design of the package of which cigarette manufacturer reminds of the Japanese flag?", "answer": "Lucky Strike", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab99bd521a8909e5c332d30", "question": "What year was the novel \"Who Censored Roger Rabbit?\" published?", "answer": "1981", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c956", "question": "Approximately how many kilometres is an Astronomical Unit?", "answer": "150 million", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdffac71cf6db9ac4808cf1", "question": "What country was the modern bicycle invented in?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba6b", "question": "Who was the number 1 ranked male tennis player the most years during the 1970\u2019s?", "answer": "Jimmy Connors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b6", "question": "The TV mini-series \"Rich Man, Poor Man\" was based on the lives of what family?", "answer": "The Jordache Family", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc07", "question": "The phrase \"cross word puzzle\" was first used to describe a word puzzle in what year?", "answer": "1862", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b116", "question": "Who was the second man to set foot on the moon?", "answer": "Edwin \"Buzz\" Aldrin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7fb", "question": "What was the capital city of West Germany from 1949 to 1990?", "answer": "Bonn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f8", "question": "What is the fear of microbes known as?", "answer": "Microbiophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398a9", "question": "What musical tells the story of a group of young artists struggling to survive in New York?", "answer": "Rent", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d0", "question": "Who was Martina Navratilova's usual ladies doubles partner in the 1980's?\u00a0", "answer": "Pam Shriver\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cfc", "question": "In which movie did Ione Skye portray a witch?", "answer": "Four Rooms", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f5d", "question": "In the series Harry Potter, what is the spell for water-making?", "answer": "Aguamenti", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015de9ffe83fe1f2a824b6f", "question": "What woman disguised herself as a man and fought alongside her husband during the American Civil War?", "answer": "Malinda Blalock", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6017376d44491cbd7c5a178a", "question": "President Franklin D. Roosevelt was afflicted with what illness?", "answer": "Polio", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5971ddf989261e916c8e09a0", "question": "Which character from The Simpsons tries to kill Bart Simpson on many occasions?", "answer": "Sideshow Bob", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff20fe531a458464a93c438", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Red Badge of Courage\"?", "answer": "Stephen Crane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff2581931a458464a93c464", "question": "What is a bonbonni\u00e8re?", "answer": "A fancy box or dish used to hold bonbons.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af25bdfb63e5727cf5a485d", "question": "What year did Cher release the single \"Believe\"?", "answer": "1999", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e8", "question": "When was the tire company, Michelin, founded?", "answer": "1889", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a953", "question": "What is the only US state with four consecutive consonants uninterrupted by spaces?", "answer": "New Hampshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ed", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for iron?", "answer": "Fe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bbd4c8a00d154d7af00b8d2", "question": "What is the name of Snoop Dogg's 1993 debut album?", "answer": "Doggystyle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5906818bff9c0647b50a8094", "question": "Which Gabor sister, who passed away in December of 2016, was crowned Miss Hungary in 1936?", "answer": "Zsa Zsa Gabor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c8a63b90aac110e416707c", "question": "What fruit oil is added to tea to create Earl Grey tea?", "answer": "Bergamot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397cf", "question": "Who recorded the 1955 song \"Ain't That a Shame\"?", "answer": "Fats Domino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4e4", "question": "What does GT stand for in the automotive world?", "answer": "Grand Tourer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e2", "question": "What musical instrument did Helen play on the TV show \"Wings\"?", "answer": "Cello", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad8", "question": "Who played Dracula in the 1931 film of the same name?", "answer": "Bela Lugosi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a292", "question": "What year did Cat Stevens officially change his name to Yusuf Islam?", "answer": "1977", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef62176ce05a3942286e5b", "question": "What is Tina Turner's real name?", "answer": "Anna Mae Bullock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b93a", "question": "What type of athlete is also called a powder puff, tanker, catcher or knuckle duster?", "answer": "A boxer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdfbb61003d27d341092bc5", "question": "How many US states does the Appalachian Trail run through?", "answer": "14", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdab9a20b8cce1e6fda7056", "question": "What is \"Coq au Vin\"?", "answer": "Chicken with wine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b298", "question": "Who was the oldest signer of the US Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff6685052a821ff76ae8b03", "question": "Around what sea did Jesus call His first apostles?", "answer": "Christ first saw Peter and Andrew close to the Sea of Galilee. He beseeched them to follow Him.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a052", "question": "What 2015 big screen adaptation of an 1980s cartoon was pulled from cinemas after just two weeks due to poor ticket sales?", "answer": "Jem and the Holograms", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a835", "question": "What US state is the source of the Arkansas, Platte, and Rio Grande rivers?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c81b", "question": "In what part of the body would you find cowper's fluid?", "answer": "The penis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1bb", "question": "Who is the lead singer of the English band \"Yes\"?", "answer": "Jon Anderson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7336deec85e375820b220", "question": "What British general surrendered to Japanese forces at the Battle of Singapore?", "answer": "Arthur Percival", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4b4", "question": "How many pounds are there in a long ton?", "answer": "2,240", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133966c", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Marge's bowling ball?", "answer": "Homer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c44c", "question": "How many chromosomes does a goat have?", "answer": "60", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59c1cefc7bd84c0ea43ad43d", "question": "\"The Obvious Child\" was a 1990 hit for whom?", "answer": "Paul Simon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb611a5dad637d903c882d", "question": "What is the Golden Gate Bridge named after?", "answer": "Golden Gate was named after the narrow, 300-foot-deep Golden Gate Strait which flows underneath it.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339984", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what was the name of Barney's snowplowing business?", "answer": "Plow King", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d1", "question": "The Roanoke Colony was established in which present-day US State?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd3", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"J\"?", "answer": "Juliett", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ae862f37f28483af1e7fdc8", "question": "What country did Hawaiian pizza come from?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c811", "question": "What spectral class does our sun belong to?", "answer": "G", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133926f", "question": "How much does the Academy Award statue weigh?", "answer": "8.5 pounds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f3e", "question": "According to legend, who cut the tree-bark rope tied into a \"Gordian knot\"?", "answer": "Alexander the Great", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c4e", "question": "Who is the Roman goddess of love?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a88a", "question": "What historic plaza is named for the first publisher of the \"Dallas Morning News\"?", "answer": "Dealey Plaza", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6013709c1381754895396383", "question": "Actor Earl Hindman always hid behind a fence in which '90s TV show?", "answer": "\"Home Improvement\", which aired from 1991 to 1999.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3e09ff048f679a45ab58", "question": "In 1906, a call for higher vitamin intakes was made to decrease outbreaks of which ailments?", "answer": "Scurvy and Ricketts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd81bfed0de9af39e9d467e", "question": "The term \"ok\" caught on during what president's campaign?", "answer": "Martin Van Buren", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b006", "question": "What war gave the US its freedom from Britain?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d8", "question": "What was the first man-made satellite put into orbit?", "answer": "Sputnik I", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fede4a26ce05a3942286ddf", "question": "In 1994, Elton John wrote the songs for which Disney animated film with lyricist Tim Rice?", "answer": "\"The Lion King\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a1", "question": "What is Demeter the god of?", "answer": "Harvest and agriculture", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3b9", "question": "In what decade was Montreal Canadien great Guy Lafleur born?", "answer": "1950s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e93a594d6f11f394a3b2d53", "question": "What sport was Arthur Ashe associated with?", "answer": "Tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597de01177980686f722d188", "question": "The word \"Sandwich\" is a reference to which 18th century English aristocrat?", "answer": "John Montagu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe734d5eec85e375820b23d", "question": "What was the purpose of the Wannsee Conference during World War II?", "answer": "Formalize the plan to exterminate all of the Jews in Europe", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8e6", "question": "What do most tourists call the Vieux Carre?", "answer": "The French Quarter", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b91a", "question": "The word alphabet comes from which 2 Greek letters?", "answer": "Alpha and Beta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c205", "question": "What year was the US an Olympic Games host for the first time?", "answer": "1904", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f70d7a9e54d890926f6d8", "question": "How many states does Yellowstone National Park cover?", "answer": "Three -- Wyoming is home to 96% of the park, including the famed Old Faithful geyser, but 1% is in Idaho, and 3% is in Montana.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febb2d37e83c707845b2114", "question": "HIV stands for what?", "answer": "Human Immunodeficiency Virus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339034", "question": "The story \"The Rose and The Ring\" was written by which 19th century novelist?", "answer": "William Thackeray", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b3231e5bf195a31e15d7389", "question": "Who owned the sword Joyeuse?", "answer": "Charlemagne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394da", "question": "What was Shari Lewis' hand puppet called?", "answer": "Lamb Chop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c0", "question": "Lake Vanern is the largest lake in which country?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af25a53b63e5727cf5a4852", "question": "Who sang the songs \"Bump n' Grind\" and \"She's Got That Vibe\"?", "answer": "R Kelly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8fc", "question": "Int the medical field, what do the initials E.E.G stand for?", "answer": "Electroencephalograph", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c06e", "question": "In what decade was Montreal Canadien great Guy Lafleur born?", "answer": "1950s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe93abd6bd93ce3a4e5f69a", "question": "Which term refers to the variability of life on Earth?", "answer": "Biodiversity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f7", "question": "What actor played the role of Leeloo in the 1997 movie \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Milla Jovovich", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f0deff048f679a45aaa9", "question": "Trypophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Holes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b378", "question": "What was the nationality of Franz Liszt?", "answer": "Hungarian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f1", "question": "Who were the founders of the Sony Corporation?", "answer": "Masaru Ibuka and Akio Morita", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e2", "question": "What image appears on The Saint's business card?", "answer": "A stick figure with a halo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc2f34dcee580c7f8fd1e55", "question": "Who said, \"I ain't got time to bleed.\"?", "answer": "Jesse Ventura", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef657b6ce05a3942286e6d", "question": "Where is the oldest annual horse race?", "answer": "England", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf7", "question": "Who developed the world's first vaccine?", "answer": "Edward Jenner", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e7", "question": "What is the longest one syllable word in the English language?", "answer": "Screeched", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e18", "question": "What famed Motown songwriting trio had their first Top Ten hit with \"Heat Wave\"?", "answer": "Holland-Dozier-Holland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909d2f6bb53d1af6588650e", "question": "Who played the lead role in the 1983 film \"Merry Christmas, Mr. Lawrence\"?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7c0", "question": "In pool, what color is the 6-ball?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c181", "question": "The skin of which animal is used to make the finest grade Morocco Leather?", "answer": "Goat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a589", "question": "Which present day US state did Ponce De Leon explore?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d6a", "question": "What prospector is cremated in poet Robert Service's most famous ballad?", "answer": "Sam McGee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9d0", "question": "The vernal equinox is the beginning of what?", "answer": "Spring", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4e65506d333868d34d731", "question": "What food did the Christian church ban during lent that help leads to its popularity on Easter?", "answer": "Eggs", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5971e13f89261e916c8e09b3", "question": "What alien species is affected by the Genophage in the Mass Effect Series?", "answer": "Krogan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb03", "question": "What magazine publisher founded a motorcycle club called the \"Capitalist Tools\"?", "answer": "Malcolm Forbes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133944c", "question": "Mel Gibson both directed and starred in which 1995 movie?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133903f", "question": "Which movie star published an autobiography in 2002 entitled \"Lucky Man\"?", "answer": "Michael J. Fox", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ab1bb0baab681b0929219b", "question": "Which Canadian city is host to the Canadian International Autoshow?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339052", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Cry, the Beloved Country\"?", "answer": "Alan Paton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b177", "question": "Which US state was once governed by the star of \"Conan the Barbarian\"?", "answer": "California", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b692", "question": "Klaxon horns were used on what type of vehicle during World War II?", "answer": "Submarines", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b59c", "question": "Who was the first deaf Miss America, crowned in 1995?", "answer": "Heather Whitestone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c284", "question": "How would you write 99 in Roman numerals?", "answer": "XCIX", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ae", "question": "What is the capitol of Morocco?", "answer": "Rabat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b583e662d71a53650ffb", "question": "In which classic children's book does the protagonist only eat cabbage?", "answer": "\"Charlie and the Chocolate Factory\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef92086ce05a3942286e7f", "question": "In what state did Bob Dillon grow up?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5906809aff9c0647b50a808d", "question": "What sporting legend was born Cassius Marcellus Clay Jr. on January 17, 1942?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba3d", "question": "What disease devastated America's population of Elm trees?", "answer": "Dutch Elm Disease", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c04", "question": "What novel portrays the life of the Joad family during the Great Depression?", "answer": "The Grapes of Wrath", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed7", "question": "Which two countries signed the treaty of Tordesillas in 1494 which divided the new world between them?", "answer": "Spain and Portugal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59524530736d4be723796b6c", "question": "What French impressionist painter died in 1926", "answer": "Claude Monet", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede5546ce05a3942286dea", "question": "What Bruce Willis action movie takes place on Christmas eve?", "answer": "\"Die Hard\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eef", "question": "What H. G. Wells title would become a Ralph Ellison novel without the initial \"the\"?", "answer": "The Invisible Man", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c081", "question": "People with a lot of hair are said to suffer from what?", "answer": "Hypertrichosis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd820a0d0de9af39e9d469f", "question": "As of 2020, how many vice presidents have gone on to become president in the US?", "answer": "14", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb2667e83c707845b2112", "question": "Which celestial body is known as both the morning star and evening star?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}]